Guide to the Andrea Callard Papers 1966-2000 MSS 156
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Oversize
  - Series II Subseries D: Andrea Callard Artist Files, 1979-1981 40 Lispenard St.
    - Original collage black and white photographs with hand tinting from AC's Custom and Culture II piece., 1979 (Box 15, Folder 216)
    - Custom and Culture II: Black and white contact sheet. Images of stairs, windows, lighting, ornaments. See folder 218 for smaller contact sheet and negatives of the same images., 1979 (Box 15, Folder 219)
    - Custom and Culture II: black and white contact sheets. Images of building exteriors. see folder 229 for corresponding negatives., 1979 (Box 15, Folder 228)
    - "Commuting from Point to Point" color photograph., 1980 (Box 15, Folder 242)
    - Andrea Callard's contribution to the Brooke Alexander Colab Benefit. Cold foil and paint, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 250)
    - News and Nutrition work. Andrea Callard's contribution the Colab's Times Square Show., 1980 (Box 15, Folder 251)
    - Planning notes for News and Nutrition work., 1980 (Box 15, Folder 252)
    - Photo background used for News and Nutrition work., 1980 (Box 15, Folder 253)
    - Newspaper announcement for ABC NO RIO "Animals Living in Cities" featuring Andrea Callard's work., 1980 (Box 15, Folder 255)
    - photograph "Half of the Heart went to Work...", 1980 (Box 15, Folder 257)
    - drawing, "Half of the Heart went to Work. The Other Half went to War.", 1980 (Box 15, Folder 258)
    - Black and white contact sheet. Images of trahs, Jeff Callard and Matthew Geller on the West Side highway at Chambers. Negatives in folder 259., 1980 (Box 15, Folder 260)
    - "Whole more than two" Richard Miller and Andrea Callard Show at White Columns., 1981 (Box 15, Folder 265)
    - Black and white contact sheet. Images of Cummington Community for the Arts, Andrea Callard, Marjorie Cohen, Matthew Geller. Corresponding negatives in folder 268., 1981 (Box 15, Folder 269)
    - Black and white contact sheet. Images of Cummington Community for the Arts. Corresponding contact sheet in folder 270., 1981 (Box 15, Folder 271)
    - Black and white contact sheet. Images of Cummington Community for the Arts. Corresponding negatives in folder 272., 1981 (Box 15, Folder 273)
    - Black and white contact sheet. Images of hostage parade., 1981 (Box 15, Folder 274)
    - Ailanthus photo collage with trees cut out., 1981 (Box 15, Folder 275)
  - Series II Subseries E: Andrea Callard Artist Files, 1982-1986 Lispenard St
    - NYC Wildlife Museum Posters. Curated by Christ Rupp. Includes AC work., 1982 (Box 15, Folder 283)
    - Collection Plate watercolors., 1982 (Folder 284)
    - White Columns Groupshow poster. April 21-May 9, 1982. (Box 15, Folder 285)
    - Black and White contact sheets. Images include More Cardboard Air Band at ABC NO RIO and Colab Mural America at 40 Lispenard., 1982 (Box 15, Folder 286)
    - "Pus Factory" drawings., 1984 (Box 15, Folder 301)
    - Planning drawings and photograph for Kathy High and Andrea Callard's Colab Street poster collaboration., 1984 (Box 15, Folder 302)
    - Black and white contact sheets. Images of Ailanthus trees and an anti-nuclear demonstration., 1984 (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - Women in Jazz Downtown Poster. Designed by Andrea Callard., 1985 (Box 15, Folder 308)
  - Series II Subseries F: Andrea Callard Artist Files, 1987-1989 Lispenard St
    - The Summer magazine of Art Awareness. Full page on The Wake Up Printshop with photographs of Andrea Callard and her work., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 316)
    - Publicity posters for DIA "If you lived here" exhibition (Box 16, Folder 345)
  - Series II Subseries G: Andrea Callard Artist Files, 1990-2000 Lispenard St.
    - Art in General window installation, Andrea Callard's "Home Turf" publicity posters, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 359)
    - Storefront for Art and Architecture. Andrea Callard "Designs and ideas for the waste stream" April 26-May 24, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 360)
    - Rockland Center for the Arts. Oversize materials related to folder 378, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 379)
    - Teaching planning diagram., undated (Box 16, Folder 386)
  - Series II Subseries I: Andrea Callard Artist Files, Miscellaneous materials
    - Art Awareness Summer Season advertisement. Avocet Printshop artist in residence program coordinated by Andrea Callard., undated (Box 16, Folder 389A)
    - Callard drawing for backyard of ABC NO RIO on Rivington St., undated (Box 16, Folder 403)
    - Pencil Sketch of trashcan and umbrella, undated (Box 16, Folder 404)
    - Drawings and writing relating to urban wildlife particularly bugs and birds., undated (Box 16, Folder 405)
    - drawing and writing, undated (Box 16, Folder 414)
    - Text, dreawing and watercolor on bristol board, undated (Box 16, Folder 420)
    - "Holding Hands around a campfire of change", undated (Box 16, Folder 430)
    - Black and white contact sheets. some annotated., undated (Box 16, Folder 453)
    - Black and white contact sheets. Images of trashcans., undated (Box 16, Folder 462)
    - Miscellaneous Black and White photographs. Includes Abbiee Hoffman television images, New York Streets, Statues, bird images, "This is Not Doris Day", Fred Krughoff errand at Phillipson Chambers Xerox Store, Reese Williams and bus., undated (Box 16, Folder 463A)
    - Black and white contact sheet. Images of fire hydrants., undated (Box 16, Folder 481)
    - Black and white contact sheet. Images of buildings., undated (Box 16, Folder 484)
  - Subseries III Subseries A: Administrative Materials, Grants
    - Materials relating to Virginia Commonwealth Univeristy artist forum., 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 509)
    - Supporting documents to Municipal Arts Society regarding "The Tenement" installation at Chinatown History Project and DIA. Includes photocopies of contact sheets, contact sheets of photo collage, slide show script, slide list and photocopies of exhibited photographs., 1989 (Box 17, Folder 522)
    - Brendan Gill Prize Information, undated (Box 17, Folder 527)
  - Series III Subseries D: Administrative Materials, Organizational Participation
    - LINE Poster/RFP, Andrea Callard on Board of Directors. [Poster by Andrea Callard?], ca. 1978 (Box 17, Folder 538)
  - Series III Subseries F: Administrative Materials, Notes and Research copies
    - Housing advocacy Met Council on Housing, Tenant/Inquilino newspaper. 19:2, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 547)
  - Series IV Subseries A: Other Artist Files, Individual artist files
    - Ahearn, Charlie. "The Deadly Art of Survival" poster., undated (Box 17, Folder 563)
    - Ahearn, John. "Shame" film poster., undated (Box 17, Folder 564)
    - Caldwell, Randi "Line O' Pine" booklet, unbound, unfolded with inscription, undated (Box 17, Folder 580)
    - Cooper, Ellen painted care package box. Inside ae papers that may or may not be part of the original care package., 1983 (Box 18, Folder 585)
    - Glier, Mike. "Training for Leisure" at the Kitchen., 1980 (Box 17, Folder 593)
    - Howland, R., undated (Box 6, Folder 596)
    - Hsieh, Tehching "One Year Performance" poster, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 597)
    - Mock, Richard Basil "Dog on the Eat" artist proof, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 609)
    - Mock, Richard Basil original copies of New York Times artworks., undated (Box 17, Folder 610)
    - Mock, Richard Basil. Spanner Poster, undated (Box 17, Folder 611)
    - Nauman, R., undated (Box 17, Folder 614)
    - Seltman, R. L. Installation and film screening at White Columns., 1980 (Box 17, Folder 624)
    - Thompson, Mark. "Sharing Work in Progress from my Relationship with Honeybees" poster, undated (Box 17, Folder 630)
    - Wells, David, undated (Box 17, Folder 637)
  - Series IV Subseries B: Other Artist Files, Collaborations and Group Shows
    - Fitzgibbon and Winters Poster, undated (Box 17, Folder 643A)
    - Cooney, Robert and Tom Otterneess Collaboration "Gas Grati$" poster, in Spanish., undated (Box 17, Folder 644)
  - Series IV Subseries C: Other Artist Files, Miscellaneous and Unknown Artists
    - "Disarm" poster, undated (Box 17, Folder 650)
    - "Push and Pull" photo poster, undated (Box 17, Folder 653)
    - unlabeled poster, television with globe on top, poinsetta flower on top of television., undated (Box 17, Folder 654)
    - "Half Magic Little Quilts" poster, undated (Box 17, Folder 655)
    - Poster, white text on black background, drawing of castle architecture., undated (Box 17, Folder 656)
    - Child's drawing, undated (Box 17, Folder 658)
    - Black and white contact sheet, corresponds to negatives in folder 569, undated (Box 17, Folder 660)
    - Unlabeled poster, spraypaint, stencil, diagrams of muscle and skeletal systems., undated (Box 17, Folder 662)
  - Series VI: Biographical Material
    - Journal entry- personal writing, undated (Box 17, Folder 844)
  - Series VII: Printed Materials
    - Adirondacks map, undated (Box 17, Folder 848)
    - Everglades Echo, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 855)
    - New York Nichiben, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 866A)
    - Ruby Dam Quadrangle map, undated (Box 17, Folder 874)
- Mapcase
  - Series I Subseries B: Colab Shows and Events
    - Talk is Cheap street posters, 1984 (Folder 83)
  - Series II Subseries B: Andrea Callard Artist Files 1973-1976, 150 Chambers St.
    - Two long drawings. Brown paper and brown ink., 1973-1976 (Folder 139)
  - Series II Subseries E: Andrea Callard Artist Files, 1982-1986 Lispenard St
    - Poster advertisement for "Central America Flowers from the Volcano". Sponsored in part by Colab. Andrea Callard poster., 1984 (Folder 303)
  - Series IV Subseries B: Other Artist Files, Collaborations and Group Shows
    - Chart created by Reese and Winnie Williams, undated (Folder 647)